ALEXANDER G BURNER

5026 7th Ave NE • Seattle, WA 98105 • (206) 390-2364 • aburner@uw.edu • alexburner.com/portfolio

OBJECTIVE

Seeking full-time employment following Spring 2015 graduation with Informatics BS from University of Washington

SUMMARY

Motivated and capable student with eye for detail and comprehensive technological and cultural background. Experienced in balancing user needs with technological constraints. Proficient in translating technobabble into humanspeak. Effective in extracting and transforming abstract desires into strict requirements. Adaptable and voracious in learning current status of complex systems. Eager and ambitious in finding enhancements.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, PHP, C#, MVC, Bootstrap, Git/SVN/TFS, [academic: C/++, Java, Python, Ruby, Racket]
- Systems thinking, Human-Computer Interaction, User Experience, Information Architecture, Branding & Identity
- Interpersonal communication, task and time management, team leadership, teaching and training techniques

EDUCATION

University of Washington – The Information School

 Pursuing BS in Informatics with concentration in Human-Computer Interaction 3.7 Cumulative GPA 	Sep 2007 – Jun 2009
 New York University – Tisch School of the Arts Studied Computer Science, Psychology, Film & Television 3.4 Cumulative GPA 	
WORK EXPERIENCE	
 Web Application Developer @ University of Washington Working with professors Bob Boiko & David Stearns to create LearnTogether LMS Building database, JSON API, and browser client using Node.js and AngularJS 	Sep 2014 – Jun 2015
 Programmer/Analyst Intern @ Boeing Commercial Airplanes Built web dashboard of IT process analytics using C# backend & JS frontend Built C# web service with JSON API to audit over 200 production servers 	Jun 2014 – Sep 2014
 Informatics 101 Teaching Assistant @ University of Washington Planned and guided discussions on topics for Social Networking Technologies Led quiz section activities for 25 students in two 2-hour classes each week 	Sep 2013 – Dec 2013
 User Researcher, SharePoint Designer & Developer @ Quorum Review Conducted research and interviews into current and future tool usage patterns Created custom SP2010 Master Pages for internal department and team sites 	Jul 2013 – Aug 2013
 Information Architecture & User Experience Designer @ University of Washington Worked with Informatics professor Bob Boiko and team of four graduate students Helped redesign online gamified learning system (gClass) used for teaching INFO101 Built prototypes & new front-end interface using the Twitter Bootstrap framework 	Apr 2013 – Sep 2013
 Mobile Application & Back End Developer @ ground(ctrl) Built company's first mobile application using JavaScript in the Titanium framework Built ticket scanning app and managed staff for entry gate at FFFFest 2011 & 2012 	Sep 2010 – Dec 2012

Web Design & Development Intern @ BKWLD

May 2010 – Aug 2010

Jan 2013 - Jun 2015

• Worked on icon design, site design, front end & Wordpress development

Built backend, desktop site, mobile site, and JSON API for room reservation system Led two talks on basic and advanced JS for ground(ctrl) / BKWLD / Elastic office

• Completed design & development of new website for Elastic Suite